Saurabh Nandy

Bangalore, Karnataka, 560048 +91 9930170738 - saurabhnandy.work@gmail.com

Summary

Enthused software developer with a passion for technology having 2+ years of experience, with competencies in backend and full-stack development, proven skills in collaborating with different teams and, building and maintaining complex and scalable applications in an agile environment. Seeking out new opportunities to work in a fast-paced and challenging environment that could help in overall growth.

Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- · DBMS, SQL, NoSQL
- · CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker
- · Knowledge of Cloud, Kafka, Sonar

- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Angular, Django, Flask NodeJs
- · Data structures and Algorithms
- · REST API Design and Development
- · Version Control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- · Exposure to ML and DL

Experience

Software Development Engineer, Hotels Amadeus Software Labs

Oct 2022 - Current Bangalore, Karnataka

- Contributed to the design, development and maintainance of REST APIs and SOAP webservices in Spring Boot and Apache CXF.
- Migrated services from legacy Apache CXF to Spring Boot, making the system capable of handling millions of requests every day and also improved code coverage of tests by 75%.
- Designed and developed a highly customizable system for seamless onboarding of hotels into Amadeus, increasing bookings and revenue by 25%.
- Assisted in the development of new services to deliver bookings in realtime to hotels using Apache Kafka, thus
 reducing latency of booking deliveries and prevent overbookings.
- Utilized knowledge of Database systems (MySQL, MariaDB) and ORM (Hibernate, JPA) to design and integrate databases in newly developed applications.
- Handled incoming bugs and incidents contributing to the stability of different applications, resolved vulnerabilities and security issues in existing products, performed code reviews, and provided on-call and war-room support to ensure customer satisfaction.

Software Development Engineer, Airlines Amadeus Software Labs

Aug 2021 - Sep 2022 Bangalore, Karnataka

- · Contributed as a full-stack developer for Selling Platform Connect (SECO) a booking platform for OTAs.
- Developed new features in SECO for air shopping & booking flows, comparison matrix, etc. using Angular and Java, following the best coding and testing practices, resulting in increased customer satisfaction.
- Documented and executed technical migration of features from legacy Aria codebase to Angular, thus reducing technical debt.
- Proactively troubleshooted and resolved ongoing bugs and incidents, significantly reducing backlog.
- Conducted comprehensive technical and functional knowledge transfer sessions, mentoring new hires and interns while providing essential technical support for daily scrum activities.

Education and Training

B.Tech in Computer Engineering KJ Somaiya College of Engineering

Aug 2017 - May 2021 Mumbai, Maharashtra

9.53 GPA

Ranked in Top 5% of college

Projects

- Notelt An online notepad that can be used to create, save and access notes anytime on the internet using
 Flask in Python. Incorporated various features into the application like the ability to add password to the notes
 for security, rename notes, markdown support, preview, etc and deployed it on cloud.
- ANTARA Designed and implemented a social distance surveillance system during Internship, that can
 monitor and regulate crowds in closed spaces to ensure social distancing. Utilised a deep learning model
 based on neural networks and computer vision to detect crowd cluster formation on existing CCTV
 infrastructure. Deployed it on cloud and secured 1st rank among all other internship projects.